mdsmartsearch.com 2011-02-25

# Privacy

MDSmartSearch.com recognizes that Your privacy and the protection of Your Personal Information is important to you, and therefore, has adopted this MDSmartSearch.com privacy policy. This MDSmartSearch.com privacy policy describes our privacy practices and how we treat the Personal Information that we collect from You when You use products and services of MDSmartSearch.com, including any Personal Information we collected from You when You created Your MDSmartSearch.com account. The MDSmartSearch.com privacy policy applies to all of the products, services, and websites offered by MDSmartSearch.com or our related, affiliated and/or subsidiary companies (collectively, the "Products and Services.") 

For the purposes of this MDSmartSearch.com privacy policy, "Personal Information" is information that (i) You provide to MDSmartSearch.com and (ii) personally identifies You. Such information includes your name, email or other address, billing information or other data that can be reasonably linked by MDSmartSearch.com to personally identify You. The Personal information may also include "Sensitive Personal Information." The Sensitive Personal Information is Personal Information that (i) is related to confidential medical information, racial or ethnic origins, political or religious beliefs and/or sexuality, and (ii) MDSmartSearch.com has actual knowledge thereof. 

To protect Your privacy, MDSmartSearch.com does not associate Your website navigation activities to given Healthcare Providers and/or medical conditions, and excludes from the Personal Information certain information that otherwise would be Personal Information. This "Excluded Information" is information that (i) is obtained via Your queries, searches or other interaction with MDSmartSearch.com, and (ii) relates to Healthcare Providers and/or medical conditions. The Excluded Information, however, may be used for the purpose of generating "Aggregated Non-Personal Information," as described below. 

Aggregated Non-Personal Information is information about some or all of the users of MDSmartSearch.com, but unlike the Personal Information, does not reflect or reference an individually identifiable user. The Aggregated Non-Personal Information may be formed from the Personal or Excluded Information, but any of the Personal or Excluded Information used to form the Aggregated Non-Personal Information has been processed to no longer reflect or reference an individually identifiable user. 

MDSmartSearch.com (or "we") may obtain, collect, retain, store or otherwise maintain the Personal Information from the following sources. If you decline to submit Personal Information, MDSmartSearch.com may not be able to or may choose not to provide to You some or all of our Products and Services. _**Information You provide to MDSmartSearch.com**_. This information may include, for example, information provided to MDSmartSearch.com via a MDSmartSearch.com account assigned to You and other User Communications, as described in more detail below. 

  * **MDSmartSearch.com account** \- You need a MDSmartSearch.com account to access our Products and Services. When You sign up for a MDSmartSearch.com account, we request from You Personal Information, such as your name, email or other address and an account password that is used to protect Your MDSmartSearch.com account from unauthorized access. MDSmartSearch.com stores, processes and maintains Your Personal Information and other data related to Your MDSmartSearch.com account to provide our Products and Services to You. For certain services, we may request credit card or other payment account information, which is maintained in encrypted form on secure servers. 

  * Contact Information - MDSmartSearch.com may request or require contact and other personal identifying information, such as your name, address, phone number, and e-mail address. Your contact information may be used by MDSmartSearch.com to create a personalized experience and for internal business purposes. We do not share your contact information with other third parties, without your consent, except to a court or governmental agency if required by law. In addition, we do not currently rent, license, or sell contact information to any third party. 

  * Other Account Information: Some of the MDSmartSearch.com applications allows you to store health information such as your doctors, health professionals, health facilities, hospitals, pharmacies, insurance information, emergency contact information, and custom personal health information and relate contact information. We do not share your account information with other third parties, without your consent, except to a court or governmental agency if required by law. In addition, we do not currently rent, license, or sell contact information to any third party.

_**Information recorded via interaction with MDSmartSearch.com.**_. This information may include, for example server-log information, which is automatically recorded by our servers from an exchange between Your browser and our servers whenever You access, browse, or use MDSmartSearch.com. 

  * **Server log information**. The server-log information may include information such as (i) account activity, including storage usage, number of log-ins, data displayed or selected, including user interface or "UI" elements, links, etc; and (ii) your web request, Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request, date and time of access, one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser, cookie identification, referrer Uniform Resource Locator, etc. Please note the following with respect tocookies. 

  * **Cookies** -When You visit MDSmartSearch.com, we send to Your computer one or more cookies (i.e. a small file containing a string of characters) that uniquely identifies your browser. We use cookies to improve the quality of our Products and Services by storing user preferences and tracking. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. Please note, however, some features of the Products and Services of MDSmartSearch.com may not function properly, if at all, if your cookies are disabled. 

_**Information MDSmartSearch.com provides to You**_ This information may include, for example, information provided to You from MDSmartSearch.com via MDSmartSearch.com-initiated communications. These MDSmartSearch.com-initiated communications, which may be in the form of paper mail, email or other electronic communications, are communications sent to You by MDSmartSearch.com, and can include communications that contain information related to Your MDSmartSearch.com account. MDSmartSearch.com only uses the Personal Information for the purposes described in this MDSmartSearch.com privacy policy. In addition to any of the purposes noted in other sections of this MDSmartSearch.com privacy policy, MDSmartSearch.com only uses the Personal Information for: 

  * providing the Products and Services to users, including the processing, formatting and displaying of the Personal information and customized content; 
  * auditing, research and analysis in order to maintain, protect and improve our services; 
  * ensuring the technical functioning of our network, including creating and maintaining back ups or other archival copies of the Personal information and other related data; and/or
  * developing new services. 

In addition to using the personal information that we track for internal purposes in the manner described here, this information may also, on an aggregate basis, be shared with and used by third parties with which we have contracted (e.g., our third-party content providers and licensees of MDSmartSearch.com' services). Furthermore, in addition to MDSmartSearch.com providing its own advertising,MDSmartSearch.com uses third-party advertising companies and networks to serve ads when you visit our site. These companies and networks include, among others, third party ad servers, ad agencies, ad technology vendors, and research firms. 

These companies and networks may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to our site in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. In the course of serving advertisements to the Sites, our ad networks may place or recognize a unique "cookie" on your browser or use a "web beacon." An example of such ad network is Google, Inc. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by Google, Click here. If you would like more information about not having this information used by other companies, please Click here. MDSmartSearch.com may allow certain MDSmartSearch.com affiliates to include web beacons within pages served by MDSmartSearch.com. These affiliates aggregate information about our advertising and provide auditing, research and reporting for our advertisers. 

**Please note that ad networks' use of cookies or web beacons, and that of any other third-party that has a link available on any Site, is subject to their own privacy policies and not this privacy policy.**

If we propose to use the Personal Information for any purposes other than those described in this section or any other section of this MDSmartSearch.com privacy policy and/or in any specific notice to You regarding the same, we will ask for your consent prior to such use and offer you an effective way to opt out of the use of Personal Information for those other purposes. As above, if you opt out or otherwise decline to submit Personal Information, MDSmartSearch.com may not be able to provide to You our Products and Services. 

**HIPPA**

MDSmartSearch.com is not a "covered entity" under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 and the regulations promulgated there under ("HIPAA"). Although MDSmartSearch.com is not covered by HIPAA, we are committed to user privacy and have in place strict data security policies and measures, and ensure that users control access to their information. We let users know what information we collect when they use MDSmartSearch.com.com, how we use it, and how we keep it safe. 

**Links and Co-Branded Sites:**

This policy only addresses this Site and related Services. Other websites, such as those to which we link or with which we co-brand, may have their own policies. These other sites to which we link or with which we co-brand might independently collect data, solicit personal information, or send their own cookies to you. We are not responsible for any use of information when you use such third party sites and services. Additionally, in many cases, co-branded services that are jointly provided by us and selected companies will contain the Sites' branding, but might not be hosted by us. In such cases, you should follow the privacy and terms of service link on such site to determine which company's privacy policy protects the information you enter on such site. Even if the page is governed by a separate privacy policy, we might be entitled to receive information about what you do when using that service. We encourage you to read the privacy policies and terms of service of these other companies and to contact these companies directly if you have any questions about their use of this information. 

Unless otherwise agreed to in writing, we reserve the right to sell, rent or otherwise share some or all of Your Personal Information with other companies or individuals outside of MDSmartSearch.com when: 

  * we have your consent (which, except for Sensitive Personal Information, shall be deemed given unless You have opted out; for Sensitive Personal Information, we require opt-in consent); and/or

If MDSmartSearch.com becomes involved in a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of all of its assets, we will provide notice before Personal Information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy. 

We may share with others certain pieces of Aggregated Non-Personal Information. Such information does not identify you individually. 

Please contact us at the address below for any additional questions about the management or use of Personal Information. 

We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. These include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, as well as physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where we store personal data. 

We restrict access to Personal Information to employees, contractors and agents of MDSmartSearch.com who need to know that the Personal Information to operate, develop and/or improve our services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination, if they fail to meet these obligations. 

MDSmartSearch.com processes the Personal Information only for the purposes for which it was collected and in accordance with this MDSmartSearch.com privacy policy. We periodically review our data collection, storage and processing practices to ensure that we collect, store and process the Personal Information for providing and/or improve our Products and Services. We also take reasonable steps to ensure that the Personal Information we process is accurate, complete, and current, but we depend on our You and our other users to update or correct their Personal Information whenever necessary. Except as required by the User Agreement, You may change the settings of Your MDSmartSearch.com account via the "settings" section of such account. You may organize or delete certain information through such settings or, alternately, terminate Your MDSmartSearch.com account. Such deletions or terminations will take immediate effect. Residual copies of the deleted information and/or terminated MDSmartSearch.com account may take up to 60 days to be deleted from active servers and may remain in perpetuity in backup systems. 

When you use our Products and Services, we make good faith efforts to provide you with access to your Personal Information and either to correct this data if it is inaccurate or to delete such data at your request if it is not otherwise required to be retained by law or for legitimate business purposes. Where applicable, we ask individual users to identify themselves and the information requested to be accessed, corrected or removed before processing such requests, and we may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, or would be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup tapes), or for which access is not otherwise required. In any case, where we provide information access and correction, we perform this service free of charge, except if doing so would require a disproportionate effort. Some of our Products and Services have different procedures to access, correct or delete Your Personal Information. Please contact us for the details for these procedures 

MDSmartSearch.com regularly reviews its compliance with this MDSmartSearch.com privacy policy. Please feel free to direct any questions or concerns regarding this MDSmartSearch.com privacy policy or our treatment of Personal Information by contacting us the address below. When we receive formal written complaints at this address, our policy is to contact the complaining user regarding his or her concerns. We will cooperate with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of Personal Information that cannot be resolved between an individual and MDSmartSearch.com. Please note that this MDSmartSearch.com privacy policy may change from time to time. We will not reduce your rights under this MDSmartSearch.com privacy policy without your consent, and we expect most such changes will be minor. Regardless, we will post any changes on this page. If you have any additional questions or concerns about this Policy, please feel free to contact us at: 

MDSmartSearch.com   
Attn: Legal Department PO Box 692 Brentwood, TN 37024

**Phone:**  
615.364.9660 

MDSmartSearch.com adheres to the US safe harbor privacy principles of Notice, Choice, Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity, Access and Enforcement. For more information about the Safe Harbor framework, see the [](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/eg_main_018236.asp).
